<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Traveler Custom Background</name>
		<description>Custom Traveler Background made from AideDD</description>
		<update version="1.0">
			<file name="Traveler.xml" url="https://github.com/Karb0ne94/CustomBackground/edit/main/Traveler.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Champion" type="Background" source="Homebrew" id="ID_HMBRW_BACKGROUND_TRAVELERCUSTOM">
		<description>
			<p>You have travelled the world, seeing its wonders and horrors with your own eyes. However you have travelled, you have lived in many lands, in the most diverse climates and under the most varied conditions. You have crossed paths with many people during your travels and are familiar with many cultures. As part of a merchant caravan, alone or in a small group, you've been to places that ordinary people don't even know exist. The big cities and their crowds don't frighten you any more than the deserted expanses, because you know how to get by in any environment.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Survival, Persuasion</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> two of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A walking staff, a souvenir from a faraway land (choose or draw from the trinket table), a book filled with notes on your travels or drawings, a bottle of ink and a quill, some travel clothes and a purse containing 10po.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Survival, Persuasion, 2 Languages</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
            		<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
            		<select type="Language" name="Language (Traveler)" number="2" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
            		<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_HMBRW_BACKGROUND_TRAVELERCUSTOM_FEATURE_LOCAL_COLOUR"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Favourite Means of Transport" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" /
			<select name="Transport" type="List" optional="true">
				<item id="1">On foot</item>
				<item id="2">On horseback</item>
				<item id="3">In a merchant caravan</item>
				<item id="4">By boat</item>
				<item id="5">By cart</item>
				<item id="6">By magical means</item>
				<item id="7">As a stowaway</item>
				<item id="8">No particular mode of transport</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List">
				<item id="1">I always have a travel anecdote to tell about any situation.</item>
				<item id="2">I've seen so much that nothing really surprises me anymore.</item>
				<item id="3">I'm always prepared to give a creature the benefit of the doubt and never trust my own prejudices.</item>
				<item id="4">I can't stand still and get bored if I spend more than a few days in one place.</item>
				<item id="5">I'm convinced I'm jinxing the people around me, so I never stay anywhere for long.</item>
				<item id="6">I like to travel alone, and even when I'm in a group I sometimes go off on my own.</item>
				<item id="7">I'm fascinated by anything exotic, be it objects, creatures or people.</item>
				<item id="8">I am condescending to peasants who have never been out of their village.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">The world is full of wonders and I want to see them all (Good).</item>
				<item id="2">Why stay in one place all your life when you can hit the road (Chaotic).</item>
				<item id="3"> It's my duty to understand other people and meet them (Lawful).</item>
				<item id="4">Every people has different ways of causing pain, one day I'll know them all (Evil).</item>
				<item id="5">The world is a vast place, perhaps I haven't seen everything yet (Any).</item>
				<item id="6">The road is my only true friend (Neutral).</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">I've heard about a place I absolutely want to go.</item>
				<item id="2">In the course of my travels, I've fallen madly in love with someone, and one day I'll come back to win their heart.</item>
				<item id="3">My journey is an initiatory task dictated to me by my community. When I have reached the end of the journey, I will return home.</item>
				<item id="4">I have a pet, a faithful travelling companion that I wouldn't give up for anything in the world.</item>
				<item id="5">I've fled the place where I grew up and I don't dare go back.</item>
				<item id="6">Every step I take takes me further away from a destiny that was foretold to me.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">Travelling is all that matters to me, I'll never settle anywhere.</item>
				<item id="2">I don't rest until I've walked for at least an hour, even if that means pacing.</item>
				<item id="3">I always end up mixing different peoples' customs and making mistakes.</item>
				<item id="4">I've made a powerful enemy in a faraway land and I hope he never finds out where I am.</item>
				<item id="5">I remain very naive and believe that there is good in absolutely everyone.</item>
				<item id="6">I'm not travelling for pleasure, I'm running away from something terrible that is relentlessly pursuing me.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Local colour" type="Background Feature" source="AideDD" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_LOCAL_COLOUR">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your travels have taught you to quickly adopt the customs of the people you meet, their accents, the way they dress, the way they behave, even the way they walk. When you arrive in a town or region, it doesn't take long to pass yourself off as a local. What's more, if you wish, you can behave as if you were a native of every place you pass through. At the start of the game, work out with your MD how many origins you can imitate. You also know a few words of many languages, enough to get by in basic social interaction (saying hello, thank you, ordering a drink, for example) with almost any civilised humanoid (here again, the GM is the only judge).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Researcher" />
	</element>
</elements>
